const questions: Array<QuestionType> = [
  {
    question: 'αἷμα',
    explanation: '(hemofilie, hemostase)',
    answers: ['bloed'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'βάπτισμα',
    answers: ['doopsel'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'θέλημα',
    answers: ['wil'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'κρῖμα',
    answers: ['oordeel'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ὄνομα',
    explanation: '(onomasticon)',
    answers: ['naam'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'πνεῦμα',
    explanation: '(pneumatisch)',
    answers: ['geest'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ῥῆμα',
    answers: ['woord'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'σπέρμα',
    explanation: '(sperma)',
    answers: ['zaad'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'στόμα',
    explanation: '(stomatoloog)',
    answers: ['mond'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'σῶμα',
    explanation: '(somatisch)',
    answers: ['lichaam'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'οὖς',
    answers: ['oor'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'πῦρ',
    explanation: '(puren)',
    answers: ['vuur'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'τέρας',
    explanation: '(teratogenese)',
    answers: ['wonder'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ὕδωρ',
    explanation: '(hydraulisch, hydrocefaal, hydrometer)',
    answers: ['water'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'φῶς',
    explanation: '(fotografie, fotokopie)',
    answers: ['licht'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'γένος',
    explanation: '(gen, genologie)',
    answers: ['ras', 'geslacht', 'aard'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἔθνος',
    explanation: '(etnisch, etnografie. meervoud kan vertaald worden met volkeren of heidenen)',
    answers: ['natie', 'volk'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἔλεος',
    answers: ['ontferming', 'medelijden'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἔτος',
    answers: ['jaar'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'μέλος',
    explanation: '(melodie)',
    answers: ['lid'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'μέρος',
    answers: ['deel'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ὄρος',
    explanation: '(orogenese)',
    answers: ['berg'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'πλῆθος',
    answers: ['massa'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'σκεῦος',
    answers: ['vat'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'σκότος',
    answers: ['duisternis'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'τέλος',
    explanation: '(teleologie, teleonomie)',
    answers: ['einde'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'πάσχα',
    answers: ['Pasen'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'Ἀβραάμ',
    answers: ['Abraham'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  }
]
const lesson29Vocabulary: LessonType = {
  id: 'lesson29-vocabulary',
  name: 'Les 29 – Woordenschat',
  type: 'woordenschat',
  active: false,
  questions
}
export default lesson29Vocabulary
